A force led by Erān Kharlan,
who betrayed the Kingdom of Pars,
パルス国を裏切ったエーラーン・カーラーンの軍が
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
was dispatched to capture Prince Arslan.
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
アルスラーン王子を捕らえるために出兵した
Meanwhile, Gieve, a traveling musician
who left the Royal Capital,
一方　王都を後にした旅の楽士ギーヴは
had lost his heart to Farangis,
ミスラ神殿に仕える絶世の美女　ファランギースに心を奪われていた
an exquisite beauty who
serves a Temple of Mithra.
So, what business was it
that brought you here?
どのような御用がおありだったのかな
I was on my way to see His Highness,
the Crown Prince Arslan.
王太子アルスラーン殿下のもとへ参ろうとしておったのじゃ
Master Musician, do you know of
the Crown Prince's whereabouts?
"Priestess, Temple of Mithra
Farangis"
楽士殿は王太子殿下のご所在をご存じかな
No, I do not know.
"Traveling Musician
Gieve"
いや　存じ上げぬ
I see. Then, fare thee well.
そうか　ではさらば
No, no, no! If you are searching for him,
I may possibly be of assistance.
いやいやいや
あなたがお捜しであれば　力をお貸しすることもできよう
Why are you looking for Prince Arslan?
なぜ　アルスラーン殿下をお捜しで
My temple was a donation made in
Prince Arslan's name upon his birth.
私の神殿は　アルスラーン殿下ご誕生の際
殿下の御名をもって寄進されたもの
Thus, it was the last
High Kahina's dying wish
故に　殿下の御身に事あるときは　武芸に優れた者がお助けせよと
that when a matter of import
befell His Highness,
someone of surpassing talent in
the martial arts would go to his aid.
先代のカーヒーナ長が遺言なされたのじゃ
And I was chosen to do so, but that
was likely done to be rid of me.
そこで　私が選ばれたのじゃが
どうせ　厄介払いであろう
Why?
なぜ
A gifted woman such as myself,
私のように美しくて　学問にも武芸にも練達した才女は
skilled in both the arts of war
and scholarly pursuits,
evokes jealousy among her fellows.
同僚に妬まれるのでな
I see.
なるほど
On this occasion,
they turned me out of the temple
この際　故人の遺言を実行させるという名目で
under the pretext of doing
the will of the deceased.
私を神殿から追い出したわけじゃ
Wait, why are you following me?
って　お主　なぜついてくる
No, no, no, keep talking
and do not mind me.
いやいやいや　構わず話を続けてくれ
If you are loath to carry out
this mission, abandon it,
不本意な任務なら　打ち捨てて俺と自由な旅をしようでは…
and come travel freely with me--
No, regardless of my mission,
いや　任務と関係なく
I do not like how the Lusitanians
force their beliefs upon others.
ルシタニア人の信仰の押しつけが私は好かぬのでな
I wish to drive them out of Pars.
彼らをパルスから追い出したい
I agree! You are quite right!
It is precisely as you say!
同感だ　ごもっとも　そのとおり
If I had to say, I would liken
their method to revering
ヤツらのやり方は例えるならば
only golden-haired, blue-eyed women
with snow-white skin as beauties
髪は黄金色　目は青　肌は雪白の女のみを美女とあがめ
and refusing to acknowledge
all others. That is their way.
それ以外は認めぬと　そういうやり方だ
We each have our own ideas of what
beauty is and what we hold precious,
美しいと思うも貴重と感じるも人それぞれで
and it should not be something
that we can be coerced to feel.
強要されるものではないはず
And by extension, I would ask
that you allow me to accompany...
ひいては　この私をどうかお供に…
Are you listening, Mistress Farangis?
聞いておられますか　ファランギース殿
Mistress Farangis!
ファランギース殿
These aren't my words
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
They're probably our words
If the whole world only had left hands
片源
Rei
时间轴
和路雪
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
Don't be the bastards who hide their right hands
There's nothing beyond this azure
The day I realized that,
I stopped looking up at the sky
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You'd end up breathing in the bad stuff, too
And in the bottomless swamp,
look, there's a bottom
In this town that's growing
even more tainted even now
Even if you just tried to breathe the air
You are friend, Baby Dream
Before I knew it, my heart
Was full of things I had to love all the way
Always losing, leaving
Even the unbearable stuff
Because I don't want to live my days
I amenting, unable to keep them safe
You are friend, Baby, Dream
I'll grow even stronger
These aren't my words
But our words
A whistle?
笛？　何も聞こえんが
But I hear nothing...
I see.
そうか
According to the Djinn,
ジンが言うには
it seems your hatred for
Lusitania is no false thing.
お主がルシタニアを嫌う心にかぎっては　偽りがないそうじゃ
The Djinn? I have no idea what you mean.
ジン　俺にはさっぱり分からん
I imagine not.
そうであろうな
Infants may be able to
hear the voices of people,
赤ん坊には人の声は聞こえても　言葉の意味は分からぬ
but they do not understand
what the words mean.
You are the same.
お主もそれと同じじゃ
You may be able to hear the wind,
風の音は聞こえるが
but the whispers of the
Djinn that ride upon it
それに乗るジンのささやきは到底理解できまい
are far beyond your comprehension.
I see, so I am an infant.
なるほど　俺は赤ん坊か
Do not take it literally.
言葉どおり　取るでない
There is no infant so full
of nefariousness as you.
お主のような邪気の多い赤ん坊がおるか
Whatever the case, you have
recognized my sincerity,
いずれにしても　俺の誠意を認めてもらえたわけだから
so might you grant me
permission to accompany you?
同行を許してもらえないだろうか
Do as you like.
好きにするがよい
However, only so long as you swear
your loyalty to Prince Arslan as I have.
ただ　私同様　アルスラーン殿下に忠誠を誓うならだが
I am in somewhat short supply of loyalty,
俺の忠誠心はあまり量がないので　ファランギース殿だけで手いっぱいだ
so I only have enough to
give you, Mistress Farangis.
I have no need of your loyalty.
私にはお主の忠誠心など必要ない
That seems a cold thing to say.
そういう言い方はつれなかろう
Consider the connection you
and I have, Mistress Farangis.
ファランギース殿と俺の仲ではないか
What connection?
どんな仲じゃ
Parsian soldiers.
パルス兵…
They are not.
ではないな
That is the treacherous
Marzba'ln Kharlan's army.
あれは裏切り者のマルズバーン・カーラーンの軍だ
Better not to deal with them.
相手にしない方がいいだろう
There may be someone among them
who knows of Prince Arslan's whereabouts.
あの者たちのうちにアルスラーン殿下のご所在を知っている者がいるかもしれぬな
I think I will follow them and see.
ついていってみるか
This man was apparently hired as
a porter by Prince Arslan's party.
アルスラーン王子一行に荷物運びとして　雇われた男だそうです
Oh-ho. How did you come by those wounds?
ほう　その傷はどうした
Arslan's men did this to me.
アルスラーンの部下にやられたんだ
He tried to kill me!
あいつ　俺を殺そうと
It seems he tried to steal
the Prince's belongings
王子の荷物を盗もうとして　こっぴどくやられたそうです
and took a nasty beating.
How many in the Prince's party?
王子の一行は何人だ
Just four!
たった４人でさ
Do not lie! There must be
a hundred times that many!
うそをつくな　その１００倍はいるだろう
I-It's true!
ほ…本当でさ　しかも　そのうち２人は子供で
And two of them are children!
"Treacherous Cavalry Captain
Kharlan"
That's why they hired me as a porter.
だから　俺を荷物持ちに雇ったんで
So, which way did the Prince go?
で　王子はどちらの方角へ行った
South, sir!
南でさ
I heard that you were looking
for the Prince, Lord Kharlan,
カーラーン様が王子を捜していると聞いて
and that's why I dragged
myself all the way here!
体引きずってここまで来たんだ
Hey, this information is
worth a reward, right?
なあ　これって　褒美もらえる情報だろ
Right? Right?
なっ　なっ
Why you...
この…
You'll give me something, right?
なんかくれるよな
Mm, very well.
よかろう
Much apprecia--
ありがて…
The fool.
痴れ者め　その手に乗るか
I will not fall for that.
Lord Kharlan?
カーラーン様
This man was working for Narsus.
この男　ナルサスの手先だ
These wounds are likely part of
the ruse to make us believe him.
この体の傷も　我らを信じ込ませるための詭計であろう
Then, the Prince's party is close by...
では　王子一党は近くに
This man said that they headed south...
この男　南に行ったと言ったな
Lord Kharlan.
カーラーン様
Some travelers say they saw
what appeared to be Arslan's party.
旅の者たちがアルスラーン一党らしき者を見たと言っています
All of them say that
the group headed north.
皆　口をそろえて　北へ向かったと
Just as I thought!
やはり
If they pass through the
mountainous region to the north,
北の山岳地帯を抜ければ　ナルサスの旧領ダイラムへ至る道がある
there is a road that leads to DayI am,
Narsus's old domain.
Perhaps they mean to head
straight east from there.
そこから東へ一気に抜けるつもりでは…
Kishward and Bahman are to
the east at the Peshawar Citadel.
東のペシャワール城には　キシュワードとバフマンがいる
We are leaving!
出るぞ
The entire army heads north!
全軍　北へ
Yes, sir!
ははっ
Believing that you have outwitted me,
私の裏をかいたつもりで
you let yourself be lured into these
mountains without question, Kharlan.
なんの疑いもなくこの山岳地帯に誘い込まれたな
カーラーン
It is always those with passably sharp minds
なまじ頭の切れる者ほど　卓の上でよく踊ってくれる
who dance most prettily
upon the game board.
You are not a Lusitanian soldier?
ルシタニア兵ではないのか
You do not serve Kharlan?
カーラーンの部下ではないのか
Who are you?
何者だ
I am Narsus and I serve Prince Arslan.
俺はアルスラーン殿下に仕えるナルサス
Forgive me.
失礼した
I am Farangis. I serve the Divine Mithra.
私はファランギース　ミスラ神に仕える者
I have come in the hopes of
offErāng my aid to Prince Arslan.
アルスラーン殿下にお力添えしたく参上した
I have been following
Lord Kharlan's company.
ずっとカーラーン公の部隊をつけてまいったのだ
Oh-ho, an ally for His Highness!
ほう　殿下に味方を
All right, let us put you to work right away.
よし　早速協力してもらおう
You do not doubt me?
私を疑わないのか
If you were with Kharlan's
company or on Lusitania's side,
お主がカーラーン党派やルシタニア側だったら
right about now, you would be raising
your voice to reveal my location.
今頃　大声を上げて　俺の所在を知らせるだろう
We are about to capture the traitor Kharlan
これから　裏切り者のカーラーンを捕らえて
and take him to Prince Arslan.
アルスラーン殿下のもとへ連れていく
More manpower is a welcome addition.
人手が増えるのはありがたいことだ
How many are currently
in His Highness's service?
今　殿下にお仕えしているのは何人か
My retak, myself,
俺と俺のレータク　それに天下無双の騎士１人
and one knight of matchless skill.
And with the addition of
you two, that makes five.
そして　お主らを入れて５人になった
Five, huh...
５人…ね
Kharlan's company is coming.
カーラーンの隊が来ますね
That means he completely
fell for Narsus's plot.
ナルサスの策が見事にはまったということか
Yes.
はい
Believing that his prediction
has been proven true,
カーラーンは自分の予想が裏付けられたと
Kharlan will come here,
never suspecting a thing.
なんの疑いもなくここへやってきます
To where the terrain is a
disadvantage to this large army.
この大軍にとって不利な地形にね
At last, I will face Kharlan...
いよいよ　カーラーンと…
Do you feel uneasy?
不安ですか
I would be lying if I said I was not.
不安でないと言えば　うそになる
But I must do this.
だが　やらねばならぬ
Your Highness, you must want for
more security with only one sword.
殿下　剣１本では心もとないでしょう
It is not the work of a master,
but it is a good bow.
名工の作ではありませんが　よい弓です
Please use this.
これをお使いください
If I take this, you will have no weapon, EI am.
私がこれを使ったら　エラムの武器がなくなってしまう
Please do not concern yourself over me.
私のことはおかまいなく
This bow will keep
Your Highness safe in my stead.
この弓は私の代わりに殿下をお守りするものです
I wish you luck in battle.
ご武運を
Thank you, EI am.
ありがとう　エラム
There he is!
いたぞ　崖の上
On top of the cliff!
なっ
Kharlan, I am here!
カーラーン
私なら　ここだ
I cannot stand by and watch you
murder any more innocent people!
これ以上罪のない人を殺めること　見過ごすわけにはいかぬ
Arslan!
アルスラーン
殺せ　ヤツの首には金貨１０万枚がかかっているぞ
Kill him! His head is worth
a hundred thousand gold pieces!
どうだ
How do you like that?
What is going on at the top of the cliff?!
崖の上はどうなっている
たいまつをもっとよこせ
Bring more torches!
How many are there against us?
敵は何人いるんだ
What was that?
なんだ　何が一体…
What on earth just...
There is nothing so weak as a
cavalry unit that has lost its morale.
一度指揮の乱れた騎馬隊ほど　もろいものはない
兵がいるぞ　追え
There's a soldier! After him!
Where?!
どこです
かまわん　逃げた方向に撃て
It doesn't matter!
Shoot in the direction that he fled!
Soldiers hiding in the woods!
林に伏兵
どこだ!
Where?!
They have archers!
弓兵がいるぞ
撃て　撃て
Fire! Fire!
ルシタニアの馬装
Lusitanian horse tack!
やるなぁ
Finely done.
この程度
This is nothing.
どこだ　どこから来る
Where?! Where are they coming from?!
囲まれているのか
Are we surrounded?
How many are there against us?
敵は何人いるんだ
A hundred? Two hundred?
１００…　２００か
なんの音だ
It's Daryun!
ダリューンだ　マルズバーン・ダリューンが突っ込んでくるぞ
Marzbān Daryun is charging this way!
D-Daryun?!
ダ…ダリューンだと
What do we do?
ダリューン
Daryun?!
ち…散れ
S-Scatter!
こら　お前たち　逃げるな
Hey! Do not run!
I took advantage of his notoriety,
あやつの悪名を利用したが　こうも効果てきめんとはな
but I never imagined it
would be quite so effective.
I leave the rest to you, Daryun.
後は頼んだぞ　ダリューン
Incredible...
すごい　兵が退いていく
The men are retreating...
１０００人からの隊をたった数人で
A company of no less than a thousand,
with only a handful of us...
はめられた
We were tricked!
We were lured into this terrain!
我々はこの地形に誘い込まれたんだ
Curse you!
おのれ
Move!
どけ
カーラーン お主に尋ねたい
Kharlan, I wish to ask you...
As a Marzbān... No, not even that.
As a knight of Pars...
マルズバーンとして…　いや
それ以前から　パルスの騎士として
誰にも後ろ指をさされたことがないお主が
No one has ever spoken ill
of you behind your back.
なぜ　ルシタニアなどに膝を屈したのか
So why have you bent your knee
to the likes of Lusitania?!
I cannot think that greed
got the better of you.
欲に釣られたとも思えぬ
If there is a reason, I beg of you, tell me!
理由があるなら　ぜひ教えてくれ
知らぬがお主のためだ
It is for your own good
that you do not know.
このカーラーンを醜悪な裏切り者と信じて　死んでいくがいい
Believe that l, Kharlan,
am a heinous traitor and die,
ill-fated son of Andragoras!
アンドラゴラスの呪われた子よ
なっ
ダリューン
Daryun!
殿下　よくぞ　ここまで我慢なされた
Your Highness, you have shown
admirable restraint thus far.
Please stand back and
leave the rest to Daryun.
あとはこのダリューンに任せてお下がりください
ああ
All right.
貴様の相手はこの俺だ　カーラーン
I am your opponent, Kharlan!
Daryun!
ダリューン
There is no restoring order to the ranks now.
もはや　隊列の立て直しようもないか
逃げるか　カーラーン
Will you run, Kharlan?!
年端も行かぬ少年を相手取るだけが貴様の武勇か
Taking on a boy of tender years?
Is that the extent of your valor?!
青二才が
You damn greenhorn!
Know your place!
つけあがるな
背中　取った
His back! I have him!
しぶとい
Tenacious.
まだだ　まだ
Not yet... Not yet!
Kharlan!
カーラーン
カーラーン　王はどこにおられる
Where is the King?!
アンドラゴラス王は…　王は…
King Andragoras is...
The King is alive.
生きておる…
だが　王位はすでに…　ヤツのものではない
But the throne is already
no longer in his possession.
正当の王が即位なされる…
The rightful king will ascend the throne.
正当の王だと
The rightful... king?
カーラーン
Kharlan!
死ぬな
Do not die...
Kharlan, you must not die!
カーラーン　死んではならん
A woman, a child...
女　子供に
Him, from the underground passages...
こやつは地下道の…
And to think even that eccentric,
Court-hating bastard would join him...
偏屈で宮廷嫌いのこやつも付くとは…
I swear, this prince is...
まったく　この王子は…
死ぬな　カーラーン
Do not die, Kharlan!
生きよ
Live!
I... cannot... do as you order!
お主の命令は…　聞けぬ
Your Highness.
殿下…
アンドラゴラス王は生きておられるそうです
It seems King Andragoras is alive.
My lord father?
父上が…
Unfortunately, we were unable
to get anything else out of him.
それ以外は　残念ながら聞き出せませんでした
My lord father is alive?
父上が生きておられた…
殿下　生きておられれば　いつかお会いできましょう
Your Highness, if he is alive,
you will surely see him again someday.
If the Lusitanian army has
kept the King alive to this day,
ルシタニア軍が今日まで王を生かしているとすれば　相応の理由があるはず
they must have good reason.
And they will surely continue to
refrain from inflicting undue harm.
この先も　むげに害を加えることはございますまい
Yes.
アルスラーン王太子殿下
Your Highness, Crown Prince Arslan,
forgive me for greeting you
earlier from horseback.
先ほどは　馬上から失礼いたしました
My name is Farangis.
我が名はファランギース
I was formerly in the service of
the Temple of Mithra in Khūzestān.
フゼスターンのミスラ神の神殿に仕えていた者でございます
I came in accordance with the dying
wish of the previous High Kahina.
先代のカーヒーナ長の遺言により　参上いたしました
いや　礼を言う　ファランギース
No, you have my thanks, Farangis.
先ほどは　危ういところを助けてくれたな
You saved me earlier in my moment of peril.
お主は
And you are?
王都エクバターナより　殿下にお仕えするために脱出してまいりました
I escaped from the Royal Capital of Ecbatana
for the express purpose
of serving Your Highness.
殿下　タハミーネ王妃様は私が脱出するまではご健在でした
Your Highness,
the Lady Queen Tahamenay
was still well when I escaped.
Truly?! Tell me everything you know!
本当か　詳しく聞かせてくれ
カーラーン隊の残党が戻ってきては面倒です
It will be troublesome if the remnants
of Kharlan's company return.
Let us go somewhere else.
場所を変えましょう
少し待ってくれ　ナルサス
Please wait just a short while, Narsus.
I would ask a favor of you, Farangis.
ファランギースに頼みがある
Will you not offer up an elegy for
the death of Kharlan and his men?
カーラーンとその部下たちの死に　弔いのうたをささげてくれないか
Some of them must have
even had family in Ecbatana.
エクバターナに家族がおる者もあったであろう
それでも　裏切りに加担せねばならぬだけの理由があったのだと思う
Even then, they took part in this treachery.
The reason must have been great.
The Divine Mithra is the god
of contracts and fidelity,
ミスラ神は契約と信義の神だが　軍神でもある
but also the god of war.
Please, a divine elegy
to mourn the warriors.
どうか　戦士を弔う神のうたを
As you wish.
承知しました
Mourning traitors...
裏切り者に弔いとは　ほんと甘っちょろい王子だな
What a truly naïve prince.
The current royal palace has
no one decent among them.
今の王宮にはろくなのがおらんな
まあ　さしあたり　ファランギース殿のそばにもいられるし
Well, for the time being,
I will be able to stay by
Mistress Farangis's side, so...
I suppose I can always run away
if things become too restricting.
窮屈になったら　逃げ出せばいいっか
Looking forward to being here.
よろしくな
４人が６人か
From four to six, huh?
まあ　戦力が５割増大したわけではあるが
Well, our fighting strength
has increased by half,
but can we really trust them?
果たして信頼を寄せていいものか
特にあの男
Especially that man.
His skill is undeniable.
腕は確かだったぞ
Assuming there are three hundred
thousand in the Lusitanian army,
ルシタニア軍が３０万いるとして　１人で５万人片づければいいわけだ
this means each of us need only
take care of fifty thousand.
Far easier now, do you not think?
随分　楽になったではないか
Hm, true. Fifty thousand,
I may be able to manage alone.
確かに　５万なら　俺一人でなんとか
本当にやりそうだな　この男
This man just might really do it.
So, we now have an earnest need
さて　本格的に王と王妃の所在を確かめねばならなくなったな
to determine the whereabouts
of the King and the Queen.
行くか　エクバターナへ
Shall we go? To Ecbatana?
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go, drifting
When a tale that is shapeless
Spreads across the moonlight
The treasure that is within you
Melts away into the wind now
Tomorrow, try to take
wing as your unvarnished self
Sometime, somewhere,
you wanted this, remember?
You can hear it, can't you?
There; that shining dream from that day
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go
Oh, 'til this dream comes to an end
"The Royal Capital of Ecbatana - Dungeons"
アンドラゴラスよ
Andragoras.
"Eighteenth Monarch, Kingdom of Pars
Andragoras III"
Do you know who I am?
"Eighteenth Monarch, Kingdom of Pars
Andragoras III"
俺が誰だか分かるか
I will tell you.
教えてやろう
It should not be a name
that is unfamiliar to you.
聞き覚えのない名ではないはずだ
My name is Hermes.
俺の名はヒルメス
My father was Osroes.
父はオスロエスだ
Hermes...
ヒルメス
そうだ　ヒルメスだ
That is right. Hermes.
先王オスロエスの嫡子で　貴様の甥だ
Heir to Osroes, the previous king,
and your nephew.
And...
そして　パルスの真の国王だ
...the true King of Pars.
Look well.
よく見ろ　顔を背けずに
And do not turn away.
Take a good look
１６年前に　貴様が犯した大罪の証しをよく見てみろ
at the proof of the great crime that
you committed sixteen years ago!
I am none other than
the rightful King of Pars!
俺こそがパルスの正当の王だ
ダリューンは戦慄した
Daryun shuddered.
No one would deny his bravery,
誰もが勇猛と認める彼でさえ
戦慄を覚えずにいられないほど　相手の力量は巨大だった
and yet, even he could not
help but shudder with dread.
Such was the monstrous skill of his opponent.
次回　仮面の下
Next time, "Beneath the Mask."
"Chapter IX
Beneath the Mask"
少年は　そして王となる
And thus, the boy would become king.